<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>SWT EToys Notes</title>
    <link>http://HPI-SWA-Teaching.github.io/ETLoad/</link>
    <description>Recent content on SWT EToys Notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Jul 2016 08:47:54 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://HPI-SWA-Teaching.github.io/ETLoad/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>About this wiki</title>
      <link>http://HPI-SWA-Teaching.github.io/ETLoad/_x_resources/wiki/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jul 2016 08:47:54 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://HPI-SWA-Teaching.github.io/ETLoad/_x_resources/wiki/</guid>
      <description>Software This wiki is built with hugo. The syntax highlighting is done by pygments.
Modifying the wiki The source files of the wiki are in the notes/content directory of the main repository. All source files are written in markdown with some hugo specific enhancements. If you want to modify the wiki simply modify the markdown files and push to the github repository.
On every push the wiki gets build by travis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Object Headers</title>
      <link>http://HPI-SWA-Teaching.github.io/ETLoad/03_image-segment/object-header/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2016 19:18:21 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://HPI-SWA-Teaching.github.io/ETLoad/03_image-segment/object-header/</guid>
      <description>The header of a Squeak object contains of up to three words with the size of 4 bytes. The first is the so called base header and is always present. The second is the full class pointer of the object, it has an offset of -4 and isn&amp;rsquo;t present all the time. The third word is also optional, it has an offset of -8 and contains the size in words of an object.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Git MergeDriver</title>
      <link>http://HPI-SWA-Teaching.github.io/ETLoad/00_setup/git-merge-driver/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 May 2016 14:22:21 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://HPI-SWA-Teaching.github.io/ETLoad/00_setup/git-merge-driver/</guid>
      <description>Due to the dual use of monticello and git, there are some problems with merging. Git doesn&amp;rsquo;t know how to merge monticello metadata files, causing a lot of merge conflicts. The solution for this problem that was presented in class is manually merging in Smalltalk first, and then committing the merged changes in git.
This process can be automated by using the filetree merge driver. Unfortunately, it probably requires Linux or OSX (the merge script itself is a bash script).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#Project Bug</title>
      <link>http://HPI-SWA-Teaching.github.io/ETLoad/01_upgrades/project-bug/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2016 13:21:43 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://HPI-SWA-Teaching.github.io/ETLoad/01_upgrades/project-bug/</guid>
      <description>The provided Squeak 5.1 Image causes problems when loading projects due to the following circumstances:
 Squeak 3 has a #Project class. Squeak 5 has a #Project class, which has become a super class of different kinds of Projects (such as #MVCProject and #MorphicProject). The Squeak 3 #Project has been superseded by #MorphicProject in Squeak 5. As such a rename has been introduced in SmartRefStream&amp;gt;&amp;gt;initKnownRenames. This rename however was not applied consistently, causing different code paths to work with different names, inevitably leading to an error condition (&amp;rdquo;Error: class not in structures list&amp;rdquo;).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Object Oriented Pointer</title>
      <link>http://HPI-SWA-Teaching.github.io/ETLoad/03_image-segment/oop/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2016 19:18:21 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://HPI-SWA-Teaching.github.io/ETLoad/03_image-segment/oop/</guid>
      <description>When an object contains an oop it isn&amp;rsquo;t even sure that this is a real pointer. Because the last bit of the oop shows if it refers a real object or if it is a so called small integer. A zero means that it is a real pointer, a one that it is a small integer.
A small integer has 31 bit (the last one can&amp;rsquo;t be used for the integer) and can be positive or negative.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Class Replacements</title>
      <link>http://HPI-SWA-Teaching.github.io/ETLoad/01_upgrades/class-replacements/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2016 13:42:44 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://HPI-SWA-Teaching.github.io/ETLoad/01_upgrades/class-replacements/</guid>
      <description>The following is a list of classes which no longer exist and have for now been replaced by other classes, usually a super class, if available:
 MultiNewParagraph ⇒ NewParagraph UserText ⇒ TextMorph  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Object Formats</title>
      <link>http://HPI-SWA-Teaching.github.io/ETLoad/03_image-segment/object-formats/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2016 19:18:21 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://HPI-SWA-Teaching.github.io/ETLoad/03_image-segment/object-formats/</guid>
      <description>This page compares the different object storage formats available in Squeak version 3 and 5, how they map to each other and how compatibility is best handled. Both Squeak versions store the format as a number internally (4 bit in Squeak 3, 5 bit in Squeak 5). These numbers will be mentioned for each format.
Sources for Squeak 3 include the article &amp;ldquo;Back to the future&amp;rdquo; found on the resources page, and for Squeak 5 the documentation on the Behavior class, for example Behavior#instSpec.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fonts</title>
      <link>http://HPI-SWA-Teaching.github.io/ETLoad/01_upgrades/fonts/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2016 14:16:58 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://HPI-SWA-Teaching.github.io/ETLoad/01_upgrades/fonts/</guid>
      <description>While loading a project, an error occured in TextStyle&amp;gt;&amp;gt;addNewFontSize: because a fontArray contained a TTCFontSet along with TTCFonts. As such an extra check was introduced to ignore objects which are not instances of TTCFont.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Loading Process</title>
      <link>http://HPI-SWA-Teaching.github.io/ETLoad/03_image-segment/loading-process/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jun 2016 11:23:21 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://HPI-SWA-Teaching.github.io/ETLoad/03_image-segment/loading-process/</guid>
      <description>We load segments with the following algorithm:
 For the entire segment:  Load header Create placeholder  For all placeholders:  Acquire class oop  While not all objects loaded:  For all placeholder objects:  If class is loaded, load object Else do nothing, class will be loaded in a subsequent iteration    Each object is loaded with the following steps:
 Create instance (with class basicNew or class basicNew: size) Write fields via primitives self becomeForward: createdObject  The object formats page goes into more details about how to instantiate and fill objects of different formats.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Test Image Segment Creation</title>
      <link>http://HPI-SWA-Teaching.github.io/ETLoad/03_image-segment/test-segment-creation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jun 2016 14:30:26 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://HPI-SWA-Teaching.github.io/ETLoad/03_image-segment/test-segment-creation/</guid>
      <description>To better support automated testing and experimentation, it was necessary to create minimal image segments, containing only specific, known objects.
Since the creation of minimal test image segments needs to happen in a Squeak 3 VM, which has no support for filetree, the following method needs to be added manually to some class in the image:
This method probably only works for simple objects - classes, methods and out-pointers may or may not be exported correctly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setup</title>
      <link>http://HPI-SWA-Teaching.github.io/ETLoad/00_setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jul 2016 19:30:25 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://HPI-SWA-Teaching.github.io/ETLoad/00_setup/</guid>
      <description>Setup Local Development Setup  Clone the repository at github.com/HPI-SWA-Teaching/SWT16-Project-14. Execute this code:  Metacello new baseline: &amp;#39;ETLoad&amp;#39;; repository: &amp;#39;filetree:///$PATH/WHERE/YOU/CLONED/THE/REPO/packages&amp;#39;; load.  Loading Sample Data Any method loading sample data requires the ETL_SAMPLE_DIRECTORY environment variable to be set to the absolute path of the sample-data directory.
This functionality is extensively used by tests, making a correctly set ETL_SAMPLE_DIRECTORY environment variable mandatory for a successful test run.
 On *nix this may be achieved by executing export ETL_SAMPLE_DIRECTORY=$PWD/sample-data from the root directory of the repository checkout and then starting the vm from the same shell.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project file format</title>
      <link>http://HPI-SWA-Teaching.github.io/ETLoad/02_project-file/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jul 2016 20:50:20 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://HPI-SWA-Teaching.github.io/ETLoad/02_project-file/</guid>
      <description>Project file format The project file format is basically a normal Squeak project file which can be read by standard Squeak tools. Most of the layers are a consequence of the history of Squeak.
 Project file structure of an Etoys project file   As you can see in the figure the project file consists mainly of an image segment. This image segment is the most important part of the project file.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Image Segment</title>
      <link>http://HPI-SWA-Teaching.github.io/ETLoad/03_image-segment/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2016 14:23:20 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://HPI-SWA-Teaching.github.io/ETLoad/03_image-segment/</guid>
      <description>Image Segment If no other errors occure during the loading process, attempting to load a Squeak 3 Project in Squeak 5 will result in an error (&amp;rdquo;Error: Segment has not been becommed into the loaded objects&amp;rdquo;) from ImageSegment&amp;gt;&amp;gt;checkAndReportLoadError, which is called immediatly after the primitive at ImageSegment&amp;gt;&amp;gt;loadSegmentFrom:outPointers:.
The documentation of ImageSegment&amp;gt;&amp;gt;loadSegmentFrom:outPointers: states that &amp;ldquo;[this primitive] will have destroyed the contents of the segment wordArray&amp;rdquo; if it fails.
 As such it will probably be required to save a copy of the segment wordArray prior to executing this primitive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upgrades</title>
      <link>http://HPI-SWA-Teaching.github.io/ETLoad/01_upgrades/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2016 13:17:12 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://HPI-SWA-Teaching.github.io/ETLoad/01_upgrades/</guid>
      <description>Upgrades This section records &amp;amp; documents upgrades / conversions which have been registered with the SmartRefStream.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resources</title>
      <link>http://HPI-SWA-Teaching.github.io/ETLoad/_x_resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2016 08:47:54 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://HPI-SWA-Teaching.github.io/ETLoad/_x_resources/</guid>
      <description> Resources  EToys / SqueakLand: http://squeakland.org/download/ Blue Book / VM documentation: http://sdmeta.gforge.inria.fr/FreeBooks/CollectiveNBlueBook/oe-tour-sept19.pdf Potato (Java) VM minimal Image format documentation: http://potatovm.blogspot.de/ Minimal Squeak Object Memory Representation: http://ftp.squeak.org/docs/OOPSLA.Squeak.html  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>