<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>00_setups on SWT EToys Notes</title>
    <link>http://HPI-SWA-Teaching.github.io/ETLoad/00_setup/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 00_setups on SWT EToys Notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Jul 2016 19:30:25 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://HPI-SWA-Teaching.github.io/ETLoad/00_setup/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Setup</title>
      <link>http://HPI-SWA-Teaching.github.io/ETLoad/00_setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jul 2016 19:30:25 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://HPI-SWA-Teaching.github.io/ETLoad/00_setup/</guid>
      <description>Setup Local Development Setup  Clone the repository at github.com/HPI-SWA-Teaching/SWT16-Project-14. Execute this code:  Metacello new baseline: &amp;#39;ETLoad&amp;#39;; repository: &amp;#39;filetree:///$PATH/WHERE/YOU/CLONED/THE/REPO/packages&amp;#39;; load.  Loading Sample Data Any method loading sample data requires the ETL_SAMPLE_DIRECTORY environment variable to be set to the absolute path of the sample-data directory.
This functionality is extensively used by tests, making a correctly set ETL_SAMPLE_DIRECTORY environment variable mandatory for a successful test run.
 On *nix this may be achieved by executing export ETL_SAMPLE_DIRECTORY=$PWD/sample-data from the root directory of the repository checkout and then starting the vm from the same shell.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Git MergeDriver</title>
      <link>http://HPI-SWA-Teaching.github.io/ETLoad/00_setup/git-merge-driver/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 May 2016 14:22:21 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://HPI-SWA-Teaching.github.io/ETLoad/00_setup/git-merge-driver/</guid>
      <description>Due to the dual use of monticello and git, there are some problems with merging. Git doesn&amp;rsquo;t know how to merge monticello metadata files, causing a lot of merge conflicts. The solution for this problem that was presented in class is manually merging in Smalltalk first, and then committing the merged changes in git.
This process can be automated by using the filetree merge driver. Unfortunately, it probably requires Linux or OSX (the merge script itself is a bash script).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>